BEN MEIER

♥ Dallas, TX **६** 608.620.4620 ■ meier_benjamin@yahoo.com

₱ https://bennnyys.github.io/Ben-Meier/

SUMMARY

A data scientist passionate about environmental and socioeconomic issues. I have 6 years of experience working with data to inform economic research and financial regulation. I look forward to new experiences that align with my passions.

EDUCATION

Master of Information and Data Science, University of California, Berkeley

• GPA 4.0 of 4.0

BS, Applied Math and Industrial Engineering, Iowa State University

≅ 2011 − 2016

• GPA 3.9 of 4.0

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python (pandas, numpy, scipy, scikit-learn, keras tensorflow, pytorch, beautiful soup), VBA, Stata, SAS, SQL, HTML, CSS, R (RStudio, tidyverse, ggplot2, dplyr, shiny)

Data skills: Cloud computing (AWS sagemaker, Google colab), Databases (SQL, SQL Server, SSIS), Anaconda/Conda, Git, VS Code, Visual Studio, Jira

Visualization: Tableau, Power BI, Python (matplotlib, seaborn, plotly)

Methods: Machine learning (clustering, K means, K nearest neighbors, decision trees, random forest, naive Bayes, neural networks), Statistics (logistic/linear regression, gradient descent)

PROJECTS

Exploratory Data Analysis of Los Angeles Traffic Collisions

Course final project demonstrating experience with EDA and visualization in python (pandas, matplotlib, seaborn)

Clustering Analysis of Holding Companies

• Self-directed project to identify clusters of financial institution in U.S. using public FR Y-9C data. Uses EDA, K-means and KNN clustering, and visualization in python (pandas, numpy, scikit-learn, matplotlib, seaborn)

Professional Experience

Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas

♥ Dallas, TX

Programmer Analyst II, Statistics

- Performed data migration and database design to on-board two new survey collections
- Developed dashboard for preliminary survey data to enable on-demand customer data access eliminating a 1-day lead time
- Developed four extract-transform-notify python automation jobs to eliminate over 700 hours of staff work per year
- Developed K-means clustering notebook and KNN clustering notebook to test proof of concept to pilot AWS Sagemaker environment
- Led requirements, development, testing, and deployment of five minor version software releases

Economic Research Assistant, Research

≅ 2018 − 2019

- Developed R script to automate the retrieval, cleaning, and validation of data for economic modeling
- Developed VBA excel workbook to automatically update FOMC regional data

Business Operations Analyst, FRB Houston

≅ 2016 − 2018

• Improved data collection and analysis of district cafeteria IRS de minimis calculation